<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Tien&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://tienng.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Tien&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:07:02 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tienng.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Volt/Amp Meter with INA219, Nano and LCD display</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/projects/ina219-lcd-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:07:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/projects/ina219-lcd-display/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Building a DIY Power Meter &amp; Logger with Arduino Nano and INA219&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In this project, I’ll walk you through how I built a simple but accurate power meter and data logger using three main components: an Arduino Nano, the INA219 current/voltage monitoring IC, and a 16×2 LCD display. The goal was to create a compact device that can measure voltage, current, and power in real time—and also log the data for later analysis. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Own Email Domain</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/posts/my-own-email-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:27:51 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/posts/my-own-email-domain/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-set-up-your-own-email-on-your-domain-name&#34;&gt;How to Set Up Your Own Email on Your Domain Name&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having your own email address at your custom domain name adds a professional touch to your communications. This guide will walk you through the process of setting up your own email address using your domain and integrating it with Gmail for sending and receiving emails. This guide will show how I set up my own email address at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tien@tienng.xyz&#34;&gt;tien@tienng.xyz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this guide using informations from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nNGcvz1Sc_8&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=12&#34;&gt;IdeaSpot&amp;rsquo;s video&lt;/a&gt; so feel free to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up SSH Connection Without Password to a Remote Server</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/posts/ssh-key-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:01:05 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/posts/ssh-key-config/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure Shell (SSH) is a powerful tool for remotely accessing and managing servers. Setting up SSH key-based authentication eliminates the need for passwords and enhances security. This guide walks you through the process of setting up an SSH connection without a password to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-generate-an-ssh-key-pair&#34;&gt;Step 1: Generate an SSH Key Pair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to create a public and private SSH key pair on your local machine. If you already have an SSH key pair, you can skip this step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RaspberryPi Home Server</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/projects/raspberry-pi-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:01:15 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/projects/raspberry-pi-server/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-a-raspberry-pi-home-server-with-docker&#34;&gt;Setting Up a Raspberry Pi Home Server with Docker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Raspberry Pi can be transformed into a powerful and lightweight home server with the right configuration. In this guide, I will walk you through my setup process, starting from installing the Raspberry Pi OS Lite to configuring Docker containers and setting up essential services for remote file access, media streaming, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-install-64-bit-raspberry-pi-os-lite&#34;&gt;Step 1: Install 64-bit Raspberry Pi OS Lite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To maximise performance and compatibility, I opted for the 64-bit version of Raspberry Pi OS Lite with no GUI. Here are the steps I followed:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did I build this blog ?</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/posts/this-hugo-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 23:00:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/posts/this-hugo-blog/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had always wanted to build my own website, no Wordpress or any third-party hosting bloats that rip your pocket! This is also for storing information and experiences I gained throughout my learning journey in the world of tech and engineering so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to crawling through my dusting physical A4 notebooks or proprietary gg docs :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-hugo&#34;&gt;Set Up HUGO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built this website with Hugo and Github Page, a cool fast minimalist combo for hosting with no databases, just raw mark-down texts and basic html, css, js skills :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archlinux Setup and common Linux Errors</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/posts/arch-linux-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 15:02:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/posts/arch-linux-setup/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-install-arch-linux&#34;&gt;How to Install Arch Linux&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that the machine is not in Secure Boot mode to prevent further authentication or you will end up with a black and yellow window and can’t do anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to the link below for how to set up a VM in virtualbox for any OS: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-uePhx7kDsEjF_vA6O1jVVHpX85VpOUiTH6j-3TIvz4/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-uePhx7kDsEjF_vA6O1jVVHpX85VpOUiTH6j-3TIvz4/edit?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Installation_guide&#34;&gt;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Installation_guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keyboard-and-font-optional&#34;&gt;Keyboard and Font (Optional)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up the keyboard layout and console font:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;loadkeys us           &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Set keyboard to US layout&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;setfont iso09.16      &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Set console font (example)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# ls /usr/share/kbd/consolefonts/   # List available console fonts&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;loadkeys us&lt;/code&gt; ensures the keyboard input follows the US layout, which is helpful if you are used to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;setfont&lt;/code&gt; changes the console font. This step is optional but improves readability in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;verify-boot-mode-optional&#34;&gt;Verify Boot Mode (Optional)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check if the system is booted in UEFI mode:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tienng.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tienng.xyz/about/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my website! I am Tien Nguyen, an enthusiast in the world of customising linux workspace and currently daily-driving with Arch Linux on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you will find contents about my experiences with all kind of technologies, ranging from programming to hardware systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m deeply passionate about technology and aspire to build a career in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listen to all genres of music depending on what I am doing atm. My favorite band is Skillet, a rock band based in the US. It&amp;rsquo;s the strong vibe and energy the songs carry that pump my will up in the darkest hours of my life ,ie. an exam :) The top of my Skillet playlist are &amp;ldquo;Awake and Alive&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Feel Invincible&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Monster&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
